Email | GitHub | LinkedIn | Twitter | Portfolio

# **SUMMARY**

My name is Winfred Edube, a university graduate with BSc in Information Technology and Business and hands-on experience with real-world project development. Fast learner with a proactive approach, exemplifying integrity and self-motivation. Fluent in multiple languages, frameworks, and technologies.

# **SKILLS**

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap

Back-End: Ruby, Rails, MySQL, PHP

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring

# **EXPERIENCE**

## HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Remote

#### Full Stack Web Developer

June 2022 - Present

- 1. Awesome Books —This is a simple website that displays the user's book library and allows users to add and remove books from the library.
  - Built with: JavaScript, CSS3, HTML5 Live Demo
- 2. Math Magicians This is a Single Page App(SPA) that allows users to make simple calculations
  - Built with: React, JavaScript, HML5, CSS3 Live Demo
- 3. To-Do List This is an application that allows a user to keep track of tasks they need to do and allows the user to mark them as complete and clear them from the User Interface once they are done.
  - Built with: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3.-<u>Live Demo</u>
- 4. Budget App This is a mobile web application where a user can manage their budget and spending. A User will have a list of transactions associated with a category so that they can track how much money they spent.
  - Built with: Rails, Ruby, CSS3.-Live Demo

MICROVERSE Remote

Mentor (Volunteer)

July 2022 – Present

- Mentoring junior web developers, and providing technical support through code reviews.
- Proposing improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance.
- Providing advice and tips on maintaining motivation to maintain longevity in the program.

# **EDUCATION**

MICROVERSE June 2022 – Present

## Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spending 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developing skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

## TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY OF MOMBASA

September 2017 - December 2021

## Bachelor's degree, Business and Information Technology

• Spent 1300+ hours mastering accounting, computer networking, and web development while simultaneously developing projects with HTML5, CSS, and MySQL.